<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title>Lorenzo's Blog</title>
	<link href="http://enz0s.github.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://enz0s.github.io/blog"/>
	<updated>2017-08-21T16:59:36+08:00</updated>
	<id>http://enz0s.github.io/blog</id>
	<author>
		<name>Lorenzo Sta. Maria</name>
		<email>lorenzo.stamaria@gmail.com</email>
	</author>

	
		<entry>
			<title>Pomodoro Technique</title>
			<link href="http://enz0s.github.io/blog/2017/08/21/pomodoro-technique"/>
			<updated>2017-08-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
			<id>http://enz0s.github.io//blog/2017/08/21/pomodoro-technique</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am reliving my habit of Pomodoro technique. I used to apply it to my life when my work schedule was crazy. Since I’m bringing in more time for myself and self-directing a data science program, I need to bring this habit back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My Pomodoro technique will follow this sequence:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Work for 25 minutes (pomodoro = 1)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Break for 5 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If pomodoro &amp;lt; 4, repeat step 1; otherwise, break for 15 minutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Repeat step 1 (to complete more tasks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will update this post soon with details of how my attempt went.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Markdown Basics</title>
			<link href="http://enz0s.github.io/blog/2017/08/21/markdown-basics"/>
			<updated>2017-08-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
			<id>http://enz0s.github.io//blog/2017/08/21/markdown-basics</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In addition to hacking my data science program, I need to brush up my Markdown basics. I’ve been coding my site in Markdown instead of HTML. The latter should have outwon me due to familiarity; however, I’ve seen the former’s simplicity as a major advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I haven’t use all Markdown syntax over the course of this site but I will list the ones that I frequently use. So far, these are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;ge&quot;&gt;* link *&lt;/span&gt;/
(description)&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;url&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;ge&quot;&gt;* h2 (just like in html; h1 or first level is taken by the blog post title) *&lt;/span&gt;/
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;## second-level heading &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;ge&quot;&gt;* h3 (which is a subheading of h2) *&lt;/span&gt;/
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;### third-level heading&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;ge&quot;&gt;* h4 (which is a subheading of h3) *&lt;/span&gt;/
&lt;span class=&quot;gu&quot;&gt;#### fourth-level heading&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;ge&quot;&gt;* unordered bullet *&lt;/span&gt;/
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; this item
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; another item
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; and so on
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;ge&quot;&gt;* ordered bullet *&lt;/span&gt;/
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/span&gt; first item
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/span&gt; second item
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;3.&lt;/span&gt; and so on
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-markdown highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;/&lt;span class=&quot;ge&quot;&gt;* syntax highlighting (just like this post) *&lt;/span&gt;/
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;```&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nl&quot;&gt;code line 1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;sb&quot;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;```&lt;/span&gt;code line 2
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jekyllnow.com/Markdown-Style-Guide/&quot;&gt;Markdown Style Guide&lt;/a&gt; has been a powerful source to me. Plus I get to use the same syntax to add notes and comments in Jupyter notebook. As they say, KISS.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Kaggle</title>
			<link href="http://enz0s.github.io/blog/2017/08/21/kaggle-competition"/>
			<updated>2017-08-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
			<id>http://enz0s.github.io//blog/2017/08/21/kaggle-competition</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m beginning to enjoy exploring &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.kaggle.com/&quot;&gt;Kaggle&lt;/a&gt;. There are tons of materials to read and browse. I will update this post when I have explored much about their competition.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Hacking a Data Science Program</title>
			<link href="http://enz0s.github.io/blog/2017/08/21/hacking-data-science-program"/>
			<updated>2017-08-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
			<id>http://enz0s.github.io//blog/2017/08/21/hacking-data-science-program</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My main goal is to learn data science. Initially my plan was to enrol myself in a data science masters program. However, after watching Tetiana Ivanova’s speech during the PyData London 2016 I realized that maybe I can pursue a similar path by hacking into self-directed learning. Now I am on my quest on how to hack a data science program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far I have gathered related links to my quest. These are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@davidventuri/i-dropped-out-of-school-to-create-my-own-data-science-master-s-here-s-my-curriculum-1b400dcee412&quot;&gt;My Data Science Master’s by David Venturi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://datasciencemasters.org/&quot;&gt;The Open Source Data Science Masters by Clare Corthell&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Naive Bayes</title>
			<link href="http://enz0s.github.io/blog/2017/08/19/naive-bayes"/>
			<updated>2017-08-19T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
			<id>http://enz0s.github.io//blog/2017/08/19/naive-bayes</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Naive Bayes is an ML algorithm that allows you to label the result into classification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used Naive Bayes in sentiment analysis. The sentiment analysis example aims toto classify if the comment is  positive or negative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dataset came from three sources, namely: IMDB, Amazon, and Yelp. I downloaded  sources from an online repository and combined them into one. I separated the data into two groups, namely:  features and label. Features refer to the comment in term frequency representation; label refers to positive or negative. Furthermore, features and label are divided into two sections: training and testing. Training refers to data used in “teaching” the model; testing refers to data used in “learning” if the model works after teaching it. Hence, I had training features, training label, testing features, and testing label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used scikit-learn to create a model. I imported Naive Bayes from the package and fit the training features and training label using the algorithm. This led to a model named classifier. The classifier is then fed with testing features and testing label. The final step led to my realization that the model’s prediction is not perfect but fascinating to discover.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	
		<entry>
			<title>Saved By Gems</title>
			<link href="http://enz0s.github.io/blog/2016/09/14/saved-by-gems"/>
			<updated>2016-09-14T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
			<id>http://enz0s.github.io//blog/2016/09/14/saved-by-gems</id>
			<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been Jekyll-ed. Yes, I am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to be a Wordpress fan until spams and food-like comments bombarded my site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One day, when I was cruising on something new to learn, I stumbled upon Jekyll, a static generator. I had no idea what it meant at that time. This prompted me to study it, leading me to realize that this interesting web magic can help me with my current site issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me awhile to get used to it. It was not entirely a breeze. I needed to do some steps before I get to see what Jekyll is all about. I updated my Mac, downloaded gems (such a fancy term to use), and run some scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was all set. Excited, in fact. I was about to launch “jekyll serve” to see the results. Then, boom. It didn’t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I retraced my steps. I even re-installed all gems. Still, it didn’t work. I searched online any related problem that was causing my failed attempt. I found out that Jekyll had an issue with the latest Mac OS. Argh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I re-worked my steps. I downloaded tools to make my web dream a reality. I placed my hope on rbenv, a gem that would ultimately resolve my issue. It did and it was amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I typed “jekyll serve” and yes, I made it. I was so relieved. Extremely joyous. Finally I made Jekyll work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such an awesome feeling.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
		</entry>
	

</feed>